Mohamed Wali Nationality: Egyptian

Mobile UAE: +971 58 8074218 Email: mohd.wally11@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohamed-w-50254333/



ABOUT ME

15+ years of experience specializing in new business development and major market expansion. Combine entrepreneurial drive with business-management skills to drive gains in revenue, market share and profit performance. Communicate a clear, strategic sales vision, effectively training and coaching both veteran and junior sales team members. Identify and pursue new business opportunities. Proven track record for first class Sales and revenue generating methods.

EDUCATION

- BA Oriental languages (2002)
- Revenue Management (2010)
- MBA in project Management (AUE, 2012)

WORK EXPERIENCE

November 2020 to date

Al Waleed Hospitality Dubai, UAE (Beach walk Hotel Jumeriah/Lemontree Hotel /Park Regies Boutique Hotel Jumeriah) Director of Sales & Marketing

Part of the opening team of Beach Walk Hotel Jumeriah the new 4-star hotel at the main road of Jumeriah located among of the most luxuries chain resorts. The role was challengeable to identify the right source of international guest who are looking for high-mid vacation with limited budget. I have created and designed rates package mostly for CIS/East Europe. I have been recognized by Fazza for creating a successful staycation package. Utilized SWOT analysis tool resulted an increase in the sales by 10% every month.

November 2018 to November 2020

Lido Hotel by Phoenicia, Bucharest Romania Director of operations

Pre-opening of the Management team, established P&L, improved profitability by 10% Provided details of percentage. increased in profits as well as decreased costs, exceeded mid-year Sales Goals by developing new special event, rate management packages and Enhanced Social Media engagement statistics result from improved content

November 2016 to November 2018

Infinity Group, Dubai UAE Director of Business Development

Managed over all operations of Hotels/Malls/Real-estate/Healthcare and control coordination between the Business Owner and operating party ensuring compliance of the service level agreement, Prepared annual business plan with particular focus on accurate revenue forecasting for the projects, determined which opportunities add the most value to the project and followed up with department heads.

April 2013 to November 2016

Al Waleed Hospitality ,Dubai UAE Hotel Manager & Group Head of Sales Head of Sales & Marketing

Exceeded (KPI) goals with annual savings of 10% by reducing operating expenses while improving quality of service, staff morale and guest satisfactions. Increased Medical Travelers Business mix 15% by regular travel & visits GCC government sectors. Managed all pre-opening activities e.g. site selection, construction, purchase of hotel furniture, fixtures & equipment, property management systems, Fire system, staff recruitment, Handled all menu development and costing. Held full P&L and operating responsibility for 80 employees; designed budgeting, expense control and monthend reporting; marketing & advertisement campaign targeted local, regional markets.

Feb 2012 to April 2013

Armani Hotel Dubai,Burj Khalifa Lifestyle Manager

The first Armani Designed Hotel opened in World's tallest Building Burj Khalifa. It was New Concept stay different with Lifestyle team who anticipating each guest needs, Built a good connection with VIP's, diplomatic and world's famous characters Maintained a strong connection with most luxury goods in UAE

September 2009 to Feb 2012

Abu Dhabi National Hotels, Al Diar Hotel Dubai, UAE Sales in Charge
Pre-opening front office Manager

Managed top accounts within the segment to ensure that client visitations and entertainment budget are met. successfully implemented the Marketing Mix the 4P's by identifying the respective markets/customer needs and comparing them with existing services. promoted all market segments with necessary action plans. Maintained high quality client relationships, through effective communication plan and service of customer accounts resulting 90% customer retention and satisfaction. Lead contributor in the achievement of 2011 targets by 7%.

April 2006 September 2009

Al Habtoor Hospitality, Dubai UAE
Front office Manager
Night Manager
Central Reservation Senior Supervisor

Achieved the department KPI's by empowering /coaching/Monitoring the appearance, Standards and performance of the entire front office team with an emphasis on training. Conducted regular brainstorm to ensure the entire team updated with hotel facilities and any special promotions, developed employee recognition programs with motivation that improved customer services & work environment. Recorded highest walk in's rates by implantation of up-selling program.